<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 11:50:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2017 E-Commerce Calendar: 52 Tips for Success</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2017-e-commerce-calendar-52-tips-success/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2017-e-commerce-calendar-52-tips-success/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 11:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22527</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The year can now begin… Your 2017 e-commerce calendar has arrived! The calendar includes preparation periods for the key sales dates in your country. Each week you will find a word of advice to ensure the success of your sales operations, boost your traffic, optimize your conversions and revenue and manage your store more easily [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2017-e-commerce-calendar-52-tips-success/">2017 E-Commerce Calendar: 52 Tips for Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year can now begin… Your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-calendar">2017 e-commerce calendar</a> has arrived!</p>
<p>The calendar includes preparation periods for the key sales dates in your country. Each week you will find a word of advice to ensure the success of your sales operations, boost your traffic, optimize your conversions and revenue and manage your store more easily and efficiently!<br />
&#8230;And we would like to thank <a href="http://www.pagination.com/" target="_blank">Pagination.com</a> for its help with integrating the template and data <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /><br />
<span id="more-22527"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">12 pages to support you all year long</h2>
<p>You already have the talent and ideas. We’re just helping you get organized!</p>
<p><strong>The main activity periods, at a glance</strong>. Thanks to the circular calendar, you will know when and how to prepare for each major sales event (sales, Christmas, Mother’s Day, Black Friday, etc.), but also for specific events in 2017.</p>
<p><strong>A word of advice each week</strong>. For boosting traffic or conversion rates, improving user experience, increasing average cart value or retaining customers in your online store, and more.</p>
<p><strong>The secrets to success of other e-merchants</strong>. Every month, a PrestaShop e-merchant shares one of their tips with you. Take advantage of them!</p>
<p><strong>A selection of tools to make your everyday life easier</strong>. For each tip, you will find a selection of modules enabling you to easily create and send your newsletters, create your promotions in just a few clicks, optimize the management of your store, and more.</p>
<h2 style="color:#df0067">Downloaded around the world</h2>
<p>“I’m so busy! The sales are here but I didn’t know the dates in advance, so I haven&#8217;t done anything to prepare my store yet&#8230; This is a key period for sales and I’m going to miss it!”</p>
<p>That is what you told us five years ago during meetings and e-commerce audits. At the time, there was no tool available to help e-merchants with the daily organization of their work. </p>
<p>A few weeks later, we created the circular calendar, which lets you quickly know when and how to start preparing for each promotion.</p>
<p>Ever since then, each year, our e-commerce calendar has been downloaded around the world and taken up by many sites that are experts in e-commerce. I am happy and touched that this calendar has been able to help you in the day-to-day.</p>
<p><strong>Wherever you are, take advantage of advice specific to your country!</strong><br />
With the help of the <a href="https://ambassadors.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Ambassadors</a>, we have made our e-commerce calendar available in more countries this year to help even more merchants succeed.<br />
The 2017 calendar is available in <strong>8 languages</strong> and customized for <strong>10 countries</strong> (Germany, Argentina, Brazil, Spain, the United States, France, Italy, the Netherlands, Poland and the United Kingdom).</p>
<p>You now have the keys to get ahead and know when and how to prepare your e-commerce site for 2017!<br />
&#8230;Just one more thing. <strong>Your store is unique. </strong><br />
The calendar also contains sections that need filling in. By you.<br />
You know your products and customers better than anyone else. Fill in the empty sections with the actions that you want to put in place, so that you can get ready and really succeed this new year.</p>
<p>“The future is the past in preparation” (Pierre Dac).<br />
So let’s prepare and build a fantastic year together!</p>
<p>Download your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-calendar">2017 e-commerce calendar</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2017-e-commerce-calendar-52-tips-success/">2017 E-Commerce Calendar: 52 Tips for Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2017-e-commerce-calendar-52-tips-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Ecommerce Email Marketing Tips to Vouch For</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-ecommerce-email-marketing-tips-vouch/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-ecommerce-email-marketing-tips-vouch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 07:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22574</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Email is undoubtedly the most powerful tool for marketing, branding, building lasting customer relationships and getting direct response. While a good email can dramatically enhance your response rates and forge lasting subscriber relationships, a sloppy one may not only turn away your prospective customers but may also damage your brand as well. Moreover, email is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-ecommerce-email-marketing-tips-vouch/">Top Ecommerce Email Marketing Tips to Vouch For</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Email is undoubtedly the most powerful tool for marketing, branding, building lasting customer relationships and getting direct response. While a good email can dramatically enhance your response rates and forge lasting subscriber relationships, a sloppy one may not only turn away your prospective customers but may also damage your brand as well. <span id="more-22574"></span></p>
<p>Moreover, email is a great tool that helps you target relevant content to interested subscribers.</p>
<p>Ecommerce Emails should ideally serve three objectives:</p>
<ol style="font-weight: bold;">
<li>Drive sales</li>
<li>Generate more revenue</li>
<li>Keep the subscribers active and get them to buy again and again</li>
</ol>
<p>Creating powerful email marketing strategies isn’t a simple task. Constant testing, analyzing and enhancing the power of messages is a must if you wish to leverage the myriad opportunities that exist for email marketing.</p>
<p><em>It is an unspoken rule of conversation to talk relevant if you want to make sense in your circle. </em></p>
<p>Same holds true in email marketing. In our busy lives, we don&#8217;t pay heed to stuff that doesn&#8217;t concern us. Taking this fact into consideration, categorize your subscribers according to their age, gender, location, past purchases, interests and most viewed items. This will allow you to customize your emails and send out relevant information to the concerned subscribers.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s explore together the tactics on how to make email marketing more successful for ecommerce websites.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">1. Design for Deliverability</h2>
<p>To ensure that your email faces no deliverability issues, you have to get your email design right. You ought to ensure that all the important email clients support the elements in your email.</p>
<p>According to latest <a href="https://litmus.com/blog/mobile-friendly-email-september-2016-email-market-share" target="_blank">Litmus Email Analytics</a>, email mobile opens are 56%, desktop opens 17% and webmail opens are down to 27%.</p>
<p>The design should be responsive so that it is compatible with laptops as well as mobile devices.</p>
<p>Your emails should invariably include an unsubscribe button with a preference center that allows your customers to select when they want to hear from you. This would enhance your credibility by cutting down the spam rate.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22577" alt="Design for Deliverability" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/design-deliverability.jpg" width="772" height="525" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">2. Email Template</h2>
<p>Email template includes the following elements:</p>
<h4 style="color: #251b5b;">a. From name</h4>
<p>‘From name’ is very important as it has a huge impact on your open rate. If you are not able to grab attention with the ‘from name’, your subject line would also get ignored and maybe your email would end in trash or get marked as spam. The best way to get heard is to use a trustworthy ‘from name’ that gets recognized by your subscribers. It’s usually your Company name or your founder&#8217;s name.</p>
<h4 style="color: #251b5b;">b. Subject line</h4>
<p>The subject line of your email has to generate curiosity or clearly convey what is in the email. For instance, “You Cannot Miss Out on This” sounds intriguing whereas “Flat 70% Off on All Purchases” is an obvious subject line. A unique subject line catches the attention of the subscriber’s lot faster than ordinary ones.</p>
<p>But how long should your subject line be? If you want your subscribers to see the whole line in their inbox, make sure it is less than 50 characters.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.contactmonkey.com/blog/portfolio-items/funnelholic-blog-top-5-best-practices-for-email-subject-lines" target="_blank">40% of emails are first opened on mobile phones</a> and thus, limiting your subject line to the above mentioned characters is of great importance. Include “Free Delivery” in the subject line and get higher open rates. According to a research, such emails get <a href="http://www.marketingprofs.com/charts/2013/11228/the-most-effective-keywords-in-email-subject-lines" target="_blank">35.9% higher open rates than average</a>. <a href="http://www.marketingprofs.com/charts/2013/11228/the-most-effective-keywords-in-email-subject-lines" target="_blank">Words like “save”, “buy”, “cheap” and “free” generally put subscribers off</a>.</p>
<p>Personalized subject lines and incorporating cute emojis in them has also shown to boost open rates. Try cute snowman, jingle bells or party emojis for your holiday email subject lines this season.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22578" alt="Subject line" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/emojis.png" width="663" height="201" /></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>Source: Emailmonks infographic</em></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22580" alt="subjetline" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/subjetline.png" width="701" height="131" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #251b5b;">c. Pre-header text</h4>
<p>An engaging pre-header text is another important element that can enhance email open rates with few characters. It subtly conveys to the customers what the email holds in store for them even before they have opened the email.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-22579" alt="preheader-text" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/preheader-text-201x300.jpg" width="201" height="300" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #251b5b;">d. Email body</h4>
<p>Once your subscribers open your email, they should not regret their decision, but feel delighted about how your email has answers to their problem. The words you choose should ‘connect’ and be empathetic rather than salesy. Talking about the holiday season, you can add a party mood to your emails with bright colors, animations and rich graphics. What&#8217;s to be kept in mind is that <a href="http://blog.mojn.com/ecommerce-personalization-stats/" target="_blank">75% consumers like personalized emails</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">3. Attractive Offers and Prominent CTA</h2>
<p>Most of the time, it is the incentives and attractive offers that drive sales and convince the user to take an action. A distinctly visible CTA in your emails will impart a direction to the users. The subscribers should be able to understand the need to act. They are looking for products that can solve their problems. If your product does not make their lives simpler, they believe that they are better off without it. The job of your email is to stop them from thinking so and take action.</p>
<p>You can go that extra mile and offer something unique to your subscribers in return of that one click. It could be <em>a discount, a free gift or an exclusive coupon on their next purchase</em>.</p>
<p>Ecommerce emails with coupons have an increased open rate, click rate and purchase rate. <a href="http://www.indonesia-investments.com/news/todays-headlines/indonesian-finance-ministry-extends-tax-incentive-pioneering-industries/item5864" target="_blank">It is interesting to know that companies invest 76.9 billion USD for incentives and promotions every year</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">4. Email Send Time</h2>
<p>Sending an email at the right time is of paramount importance if you want to get your email opened. Your customers would obviously not want to receive your email promoting discounts at 2 AM. Engage your customers at the optimal timing to get best results from your email campaign.</p>
<p>According to Mailchimp, <a href="https://blog.mailchimp.com/insights-from-mailchimps-send-time-optimization-system/" target="_blank">the best day of the week to send emails is Thursday</a>. Moreover, the optimal send time is 10AM in the recipients’ own time zones.</p>
<p>But to achieve the best engagement rate, it is advisable that you keep monitoring your email analytics. Have a close look on the times that work the best for you so that you do not get lost in the inbox.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">5. Email Automation</h2>
<p>It is important to let your subscribers know that you value their relationship. Sending out automated emails really works well to engage them and encourage repeat sales in ecommerce email marketing.</p>
<p>Automation saves the effort of manually sending out a personalized email to your subscribers. You can design an email communication schedule and accordingly address the particular subscriber concerns throughout the email lifecycle.</p>
<p>Once your subscriber signs up for your newsletter or confirms the first order, you can start off your drive of automated emails starting with welcome emails, promotional emails, transactional emails and emails for shipping information.</p>
<p>Cart abandonment emails can also be triggered if the subscriber leaves an item in the cart. Moreover, you can even send product recommendations in the cart abandonment email or on completion of a purchase.</p>
<p>Think out of the box and engage customers with some unique ideas that can help you promote your brand.<br />
As the holiday season is fast approaching, you can consider the following automated emails:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22575" alt="sur-la-table" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/sur-la-table.jpg" width="236" height="1254" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Last-minute gift ideas</li>
<li>Requests to leave a feedback and refer to friends and family members with exclusive festive offers on sign up</li>
<li>Cross-selling emails</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22576" alt="your-next-box" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/01/your-next-box.jpg" width="500" height="1495" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">6. Don&#8217;t miss out on testing your email</h2>
<p>Email marketers usually think that it takes up too much time to A/B test emails but that small investment can improve results to a great extent. Testing allows you to evaluate the best offer for the entire customer base as well as helps you determine which groups of customers choose which specific offers.</p>
<p><em>Test your email ALWAYS before you hit the SEND button. </em></p>
<p>Ultimately, email marketing is all about creating relevancy and abiding by it in order to prevent customers from unsubscribing. Take the learning into future campaigns and make sure that you test a few times just to be sure.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;">Wrap Up</h2>
<p>You can run successful holiday email campaigns without actually being * THAT * ecommerce website which sends out overly frequent and incoherent emails. Creative emails that deliver something apart from “plain marketing” and sales gimmicks are what customers are actually looking for. The results you get with successful email marketing are nothing short of astounding.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Author Bio:</span></strong></p>
<p>Kevin is the Head of Marketing at <a href="http://www.emailmonks.com/" target="_blank">EmailMonks</a> &#8211; one of the fastest growing Email design and coding companies, specializes in crafting beautiful email design, <a href="http://www.emailmonks.com/psd-to-email/psd-to-email-html-service.html" target="_blank">PSD to Responsive Email</a> HTML conversion and much more. He loves gadgets, bikes, jazz, and breathes ‘email marketing’. He is a brand magician who loves to engage and share insights with fellow marketers. You can follow him on <a href="https://twitter.com/imkevin_monk" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-ecommerce-email-marketing-tips-vouch/">Top Ecommerce Email Marketing Tips to Vouch For</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-ecommerce-email-marketing-tips-vouch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Ariel and Lucas, Ambassadors of the month &#124; December 2016</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-ariel-lucas-ambassadors-month-december-2016/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-ariel-lucas-ambassadors-month-december-2016/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 07:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[floreravaud]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Ambassadors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22547</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Ariel Spampinato and Lucas Vitale, our Ambassadors in Argentina, have organized 5 meetups this year gathering almost 400 people. They were among our very first ambassadors and have, since they joined the program, been amazing contributors both online and offline. After the success of their last meetup in Buenos Aires on December 7th, we chose [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-ariel-lucas-ambassadors-month-december-2016/">Meet Ariel and Lucas, Ambassadors of the month | December 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ariel Spampinato and Lucas Vitale, our Ambassadors in Argentina, have organized 5 meetups this year gathering almost 400 people. They were among our very first ambassadors and have, since they joined the program, been amazing contributors both online and offline. After the success of their last meetup in Buenos Aires on December 7th, we chose them as Ambassadors of December! Check out below their answers to our questions.<span id="more-22547"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About you</h2>
<p><strong>Three words to best describe you:</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: Self-taught developer, music lover and PrestaShop fan.<br />
<strong>A</strong>: Assertive, persistent and soccer fan</p>
<p><strong>If you were to write a book about yourself, what would you name it?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: “The eternal night” because all my life I have worked at night<br />
<strong>A</strong>: “Lonely planet by Ariel” because I love travelling</p>
<p><strong>What is your hidden talent?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: Composing music, surely<br />
<strong>A</strong>: Cooking any dish</p>
<p><strong>A favorite line from a movie?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: &#8220;Roads? Where we&#8217;re going we don&#8217;t need roads.&#8221; (Back to the Future)<br />
<strong>A</strong>: “Going in one more round when you don’t think you can. That’s what makes all the difference in your life” Rocky Balboa (Rocky IV)</p>
<p><strong>If you could travel anywhere right now, where would you go and why?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: There are hundreds of places to go, but surely it would be Rome. When I was there, I felt like I belonged.<br />
<strong>A</strong>: I’d go to Andalucía (Spain) because it boasts a remarkable history, the most breathtaking architecture and fantastic cities such as Granada, Sevilla and Córdoba.</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About your country</h2>
<p><strong>What is your favorite local food or drink?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: In Argentina we have the best Roast, and drink is surely the Fernet with Cola<br />
<strong>A</strong>: My favorite dish is “asado” paired with Malbec wine</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22549" alt="asado-argentino" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/12/asado-argentino.jpg" width="992" height="661" /><br />
<em>Asado argentino | Credits : Max Besser Jirkal</em></p>
<p><strong>Give us a fun fact about your country:</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: Well, we have many inventions used worldwide. To name a few: fingerprint registration system and cardiac bypass. You&#8217;re welcome <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /><br />
<strong>A</strong>: The longest avenue in the world is Avenida Rivadavia, it is located in Buenos Aires and it’s 22 miles (35 km) long. Additionally, we have two world famous Argentineans: Pope Francis and Lionel Messi.</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About PrestaShop</h2>
<p><strong>What is your favorite PrestaShop store?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: This is one of the best: <a href="http://www.headict.com/" target="_blank">http://www.headict.com/</a><br />
<strong>A</strong>: <a href="https://www.fischkaufhaus.de/" target="_blank">https://www.fischkaufhaus.de/</a></p>
<p><strong>What opportunities does PrestaShop provide in your country?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: PrestaShop has many advantages over other solutions currently used here. The first is cost, and the second is that it is not a canned system. Not only has it provided flexibility and ease of use never seen in ecommerce, but it also has one of the largest catalogs of modules and templates on <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Addons</a>. It is a great tool for those who want to start selling online and for developers who have to suggest to a client an e-commerce software.<br />
<strong>A</strong>: Every day, PrestaShop offers new modules which help personalize stores. For example in Argentina, Mercado Pago, Todo Pago, electronic invoices or Andreani for logistics. This is even better knowing that ecommerce is expanding rapidly in Argentina</p>
<p><strong>What is your feedback on the new major version, PrestaShop 1.7?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: I see a huge potential for PrestaShop 1.7. While things were very simplified in the back office and front office, it has improved user experience. The store is much faster than with PrestaShop 1.6, and surely with the following updates, you will get a nearly perfect product.<br />
<strong>A</strong>: From my point of view, PrestaShop 1.7 is one of the most interesting projects right now because it lets people build their own ecommerce platforms making them less dependent on big companies. Great improvements were made with this version and now the modules are very easy to develop.</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About being an Ambassador</h2>
<p><strong>What is your proudest moment as a PrestaShop Ambassador?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: My proudest moment is when I can help users with questions/problems they have with PrestaShop. As I have known PrestaShop since version 1.0, I am able to help the majority of community members solve their installation and configuration problems. I am happy to share my knowledge with the rest of the community.<br />
<strong>A</strong>: Apart from all those great meetups, what I am most proud of are all the community members that make this experience possible. Since 2015, over 1000 Argentinian PrestaShop fans got together to learn about PrestaShop, hack on code, and trade PrestaShop secrets. We enjoyed perfect meetings in which knowledge, experience, great food and drinks are shared.</p>
<p><strong>What do you like the most about being an Ambassador?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: Becoming a millionaire with PrestaShop &#8230; just kidding. I have met wonderful people in meetups, and have received constant feedback in our Facebook group where everyone is willing to help each other without any particular interest.<br />
<strong>A</strong>: I feel very passionate about helping shops and their owners in establishing and realizing great goals. I will be happy to continue helping the community as much as I can. Becoming an Ambassador and facilitator has also been a great way to liberate my fear of public speaking and presenting <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p><strong>A last word?</strong><br />
<strong>L</strong>: Last but not the least. Meeting Ariel Spampinato thanks to the Ambassador program was really great. Since being in the program, we have become friends, almost like brothers. <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /><br />
<strong>A</strong>: Thanks PrestaShop for your support since March 2015 regarding the creation and development of a community in Buenos Aires. Last but not least, thanks for giving me the opportunity to share tasks with MY FRIEND Lucas.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you very much Ariel and Lucas!</strong><br />
Find out more about <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/ambassador/ariel-spampinato" target="_blank">Ariel’s profile</a> and <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/ambassador/lucas-vitale" target="_blank">Lucas’s profile</a>.<a href="https://www.meetup.com/PrestaShop-Buenos-Aires/" target="_blank"> Join their meetup group</a>!<br />
Do you want to become a PrestaShop Ambassador? <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/application-form" target="_blank">Apply now</a>.<br />
Happy holiday season and see you next month <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-ariel-lucas-ambassadors-month-december-2016/">Meet Ariel and Lucas, Ambassadors of the month | December 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-ariel-lucas-ambassadors-month-december-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop 1.7: Help translate software</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-help-translate-software/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-help-translate-software/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Even]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22523</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop, the free and open-source software, owes a great deal to its community, which helps improve it every day. There are lots of ways to pitch in, from modifying the source code, or providing feedback on Forge, to creating modules or even participating in user tests. Although more discreet, the community’s involvement in the PrestaShop [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-help-translate-software/">PrestaShop 1.7: Help translate software</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop, the free and open-source software, owes a great deal to its community, which helps improve it every day. There are lots of ways to pitch in, from modifying the <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/PrestaShop" target="_blank">source code</a>, or providing feedback on <a href="http://forge.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">Forge</a>, to creating <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/" target="_blank">modules</a> or even participating in user tests. Although more discreet, the community’s involvement in the <a href="https://crowdin.com/project/prestashop-official" target="_blank">PrestaShop translation project</a> has nonetheless made it possible to make the software available in nearly 65 languages. That lets sellers around the world open their shops for free and in their own language.<span id="more-22523"></span></p>
<p>With the arrival of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/1.7" target="_blank">version 1.7</a> and new features, there’s new content that needs to be translated. Now more than ever before, PrestaShop needs its community to rally together.</p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b;">Translate PrestaShop</h2>
<p>Our translation project involves translating the PrestaShop software into more than 80 languages. In true open-source fashion, anyone who wants to help is welcome to do so. Some languages are already done (but improvements can always be made), while others are still being translated, and some are barely started.</p>
<p>Do you want to join the translation community? It’s easy:</p>
<ul>
<li>Create an account on <a href="https://crowdin.com/project/prestashop-official" target="_blank">Crowdin</a>.</li>
<li>Request to join the PrestaShop project for the language you want to translate.</li>
<li>Translate the software from English.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can find more information on our <a href="https://crowdin.com/project/prestashop-official" target="_blank">translation project page</a> (in English).<br />
<img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/12/translator.jpg" alt="PrestaShop 1.7: Help translate software" width="339" height="285" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22525" /></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5b;">Thanks to our community of translators</h2>
<p>Since the project was launched on Crowdin in 2014, <strong>more than 1,100 translators have translated more than 3 million words in 72 languages</strong>. That’s huge!</p>
<p>To highlight the translators’ work and thank them, we recently created a site in their honor. That’s where you can find the biggest contributors since the launch of the 1.7 version. You can also follow the progress of ongoing translations:</p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #df0067;border: 1px solid #df0067;border-bottom: 3px solid #df0067;margin: 10px 0 20px;color: #fff" href="http://translators.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">Meet the PrestaShop translators</a></div>
<p>If you’re thinking of participating in PrestaShop’s translation project and want to know more, take a look at the <a href="http://build.prestashop.com/assets/ext/PrestaShop_Translator_Guide.pdf" target="_blank">translator’s guide</a> (in English), or contact us at <a href="mailto:translation@prestashop.com">translation@prestashop.com</a> <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-help-translate-software/">PrestaShop 1.7: Help translate software</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-1-7-help-translate-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to become the leader in your niche market, an interview with Skylantern</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/become-leader-niche-market-interview-skylantern/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/become-leader-niche-market-interview-skylantern/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 10:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Oftentimes, developing your activity calls for fleshing out your offering in new markets or strategically positioning yourself in a niche outside of your market&#8217;s typical scope. The e-commerce site Skylantern opted for the latter! After thoroughly reworking their product offering and SEO, the company became the top online lantern seller in 2007 and have held [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/become-leader-niche-market-interview-skylantern/">How to become the leader in your niche market, an interview with Skylantern</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oftentimes, developing your activity calls for fleshing out your offering in new markets or strategically positioning yourself in a niche outside of your market&#8217;s typical scope.</p>
<p><span id="more-22539"></span>The e-commerce site Skylantern opted for the latter! After thoroughly reworking their product offering and SEO, the company became the top online lantern seller in 2007 and have held their position ever since!</p>
<p>As product experts with a competitive pricing scheme, the store has reached a wide range of consumers and professionals, both in France and abroad.</p>
<p>In this video, Founder and CEO of Skylantern Benjamin Hamon shares his keys for success and offers some helpful advice, so you too can tap in to a new niche market!</p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cOAcp8uUQQU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=skylantern"> Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/become-leader-niche-market-interview-skylantern/">How to become the leader in your niche market, an interview with Skylantern</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/become-leader-niche-market-interview-skylantern/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Keys To Successful Post-Holiday Marketing</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-keys-successful-post-holiday-marketing/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-keys-successful-post-holiday-marketing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 19:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22517</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the eCommerce businesses’ biggest challenges after the holidays is how to market to customers who are marketed out? After they’ve been bombarded with sales and discounts and offers from Black Friday on, how can marketers coax them out of the post-holiday slump? Offering your customers a fresh perspective for the New Year, encouraging [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-keys-successful-post-holiday-marketing/">7 Keys To Successful Post-Holiday Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the eCommerce businesses’ biggest challenges after the holidays is how to market to customers who are marketed out? After they’ve been bombarded with sales and discounts and offers from Black Friday on, how can marketers coax them out of the post-holiday slump?</p>
<p>Offering your customers a fresh perspective for the New Year, encouraging them to buy something for themselves, nurturing new loyalty club members with targeted offers and other strategies can all help bring customers to your site and keep your sales from taking a nosedive.</p>
<p>Here how to have a high-performing post-holiday season:<span id="more-22517"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">1. Offer big sales on leftover holiday stock</h2>
<p>Some people live for post-holiday liquidations. And even those who don’t usually participate in them can be tempted by a sale that’s too good to pass up.</p>
<p>It’s also a great way for you to get rid of retail “perishables” like food, fads or anything with 2016 blazoned on it. Deep discounts help drive traffic to your site to get rid of old stock, and while they’re at it, customers might pick up some other items too.</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">2. Grant permission to self-indulge</h2>
<p>Many people enjoy the holidays, but it can also be very stressful with all the planning, cooking, cleaning, buying, traveling, dealing with family dynamics, etc.</p>
<p>The holidays are also about giving to others, and after the festivities are over, your customers may be in need of something that offers a dose of “this is for me.”</p>
<p>Switch it up and market to the customer who wants to feel good about self-gifting.</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">3. Change the focus to New Year’s</h2>
<p>Come January 1, holiday hedonism turns into the portrait of austerity and self-restraint. Quitting drinking, quitting smoking, losing weight, eating healthier and other similar resolutions top the list every year.</p>
<p>Ads that suggest <a href="https://blog.kissmetrics.com/after-the-holiday-spike/" target="_blank">helping customers with their New Year’s resolutions</a> can bring in results. Messages about health, positive outlooks, renewal, make-overs and plans for the future all have a resolution-y ring to them.</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">4. Use their holiday purchase history</h2>
<p>This can be tricky because customers were often buying gifts for other people in the months leading up to the holidays. That means that you should make the discount or promotion shareable.</p>
<p>Target the customer who bought the product, but make sure they understand that someone else can use the discount. If, for example, they bought a Keurig coffee maker pre-holiday, send them a discount on related items such as coffee pods, coffee mugs, coasters and other relevant items.</p>
<p>Encourage them to share the discount with friends. That way you cover all the bases if the gift was for themselves or another person AND it gives you the opportunity to increase you customer base if they do share the promotion.</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">5. Conduct a poll</h2>
<p>Start the New Year off by communicating directly with your customers with a poll. Polls are a really good way to engage your client base. They accomplish a lot of things:</p>
<ul>
<li>They get customers thinking about your business.</li>
<li>They offer customers a place to voice their praise or criticism.</li>
<li>They give you an insight into what you need to improve.</li>
</ul>
<p>Through polls, you can find out things like what new items they plan to buy this year, what’s more important to them price or quality, how satisfied they are with your services, which platform they most prefer to receive messages (social, SMS or email) and other information.</p>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">6. Nurture clients with SMS</h2>
<p>If you did a big SMS opt-in campaign push for the holidays, now’s the time when it’s really going to pay off. And if you haven’t done one yet, now’s the good time to start.</p>
<p>Don’t leave your customers hanging once the holidays have passed. Instead, <a href="https://www.textmagic.com/blog/brands-use-sms-texting-in-business/" target="_blank">continue building the relationship with these and other SMS marketing ideas</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Personalized messages.</em> Give your message a personal touch by using your client’s name. Use their purchasing preferences to send out the promotions on items they might like.</li>
<li><em>Special discounts only for SMS loyalty club members.</em> Make your promotions unique to SMS customers so they see the benefit of having signed up and have an incentive to stay opted in.</li>
<li><em>Useful tips.</em> Offer advice on how to care for a product they bought.</li>
<li><em>Customer service.</em> Let them know you received a returned item and send a confirmation of credit issued to them via text. If they’ve ordered a new product, keep them updated on the shipping status with an SMS message.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #cf763a;">7. Use social media</h2>
<p>Social media works as a marketing platform any time of the year, including post-holiday. Use photos and videos to promote discounts and show off new merchandise. <a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-tips-for-successful-facebook-contests/" target="_blank">Running contests on social media</a> is a popular way to get people to visit your site. Most retailers run pre-holiday contests.</p>
<p>Be unconventional and run a post-holiday contest. For example, participants could post their New Year’s resolutions to enter a sweepstakes.</p>
<p>Have you already tried out one of these post-holiday marketing tips? Or maybe you have your own? Share with us in comments!</p>
<p><em>Alexa Lemzy is the customer service specialist and content editor at <a href="https://www.textmagic.com/" target="_blank">TextMagic</a>. She writes about best marketing pactices and customer service techniques, and focuses on small businesses and eCommerce. Feel free to reach her at <a href="https://twitter.com/Alexa_Lemzy" target="_blank">@Alexa_Lemzy</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-keys-successful-post-holiday-marketing/">7 Keys To Successful Post-Holiday Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/7-keys-successful-post-holiday-marketing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everything you need to know about Google&#8217;s possum algorithm</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/everything-need-know-googles-possum-algorithm/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/everything-need-know-googles-possum-algorithm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eva Lacalle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22503</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s no secret that local results on Google have experienced a spike recently, and the most recent changes to the company&#8217;s search algorithm have continued this trend. Although not yet confirmed by Google, local search results have been pursuing a steady climb since September and SEO experts are now abuzz about the company&#8217;s new algorithm, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/everything-need-know-googles-possum-algorithm/">Everything you need to know about Google&#8217;s possum algorithm</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s no secret that <strong>local results on Google have experienced a spike recently</strong>, and the most recent changes to the company&#8217;s search algorithm have continued this trend. Although <strong>not yet confirmed by Google</strong>, local search results have been pursuing a steady climb since September and <strong>SEO experts are now abuzz about the company&#8217;s new algorithm</strong>, which they say has accounted for a high number of possums. In this article, we explain everything you need to know to benefit from the new advantages of Google&#8217;s most recent changes.<span id="more-22503"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#5279b7">Why are they called possums?</h2>
<p>First of all, we&#8217;d like to specify that Google has not confirmed any changes to its local results algorithm. As such, <strong>the unofficial name</strong> is merely <strong>a term chosen by SEO experts</strong>. To be more specific, the local result visibility expert <a href="https://twitter.com/philrozek" target="_blank">Phil Rozek</a> suggested it when certain companies told him that their web pages had disappeared from Google My Business. In reality, they hadn&#8217;t disappeared, but were “playing dead” or — in his words — &#8220;playing possum.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Google was actually filtering a whole lot of results from Google My Business</strong>, which made business owners think that the tech company had purposefully scratched them off the list. And so was born a new and improved local SEO option for quality and content links.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5279b7">What effects will these changes have?</h2>
<p>From the looks of it, <strong>the changes directly affect local results and those on Google Maps</strong>, modifying sites listed in 3-packs of local results (formerly 7-packs) and those displayed when clicking on &#8220;more sites.&#8221; As always, these changes are visible on everything in the Google USA SERP, although it can be expected that the changes will be gradually applied in all supported countries. It is also likely that you&#8217;ll soon see a difference for customized pages affected by the changes. In other words, you will be able to anticipate changes to local SEO.</p>
<p>All in all, given what has been observed in recent weeks, the algorithm is <strong>penalizing pages that have the same domain name or telephone number on Google My Business. Pages that do not indicate their location are not exempt</strong>, nor are those for which the location doesn&#8217;t correspond with business user searches on Google.</p>
<h2 style="color:#5279b7">Who has benefited from this?</h2>
<p>Although local searches put some pages at a disadvantage, others have seen major benefits from the algorithm changes, with overnight spikes in 3-pack rankings on Google in some cases. Now for some of the changes at SEO level.</p>
<h4 style="color:#5279b7">Improvements for businesses located in city limits</h4>
<p>When Google local SEO was redone, businesses located on the edge of city limits began having problems improving their ranking, given the number of competitors inside the city. According to Google, however, some of these businesses are located outside of the locality they feel they belong to.<br />
Nevertheless, since the algorithm change, some pages (with an accurate SEO positioning) have seen their rankings go up automatically. Google has begun taking this into account for its local results as well.</p>
<h4 style="color:#5279b7">Filtering by address to improve user experience</h4>
<p>In the past, Google has used domain and telephone number to filter duplicates in local results. Following the changes made to its algorithm, Google will also <strong>evaluate and filter multiple accounts with the same physical address so that only one of the pages is displayed</strong>. For example, imagine you&#8217;re a specialized law firm with lawyers practicing different types of law. You would only be allowed one account per firm or per branch of law (marriage, labor, criminal, etc.). Another example could be a private hospital, for which specialists would have their own cabinet. </p>
<p>If each individual branch is displayed with the same address and on the same page, Google will consider these to be duplicate content, which the SEO would filter. Only the result with the highest placed local search result would be shown. Take the example of searching for a lawyer: what is the point of showing you the same address three or four times? </p>
<p>Although Google has been doing this for some time, things have changed. Now, each time that businesses are filtered, they are penalized or promoted so that the search engine can determine one&#8217;s pertinence over another in result lists and rank them in the local SEO results.</p>
<h4 style="color:#5279b7">Physical location of users — an increasingly important concept</h4>
<p>This is harmful to the SEO ranking of businesses that deal in a broad but local geographic location because the system benefits the most local businesses. Even if results are in a nearby neighboring region, <strong>Google will give priority to the businesses that are closest to a user</strong> at the moment they hit search. Google&#8217;s SERP will be different for &#8220;service+city&#8221; queries, even when the search request is for an exact match (all the same keywords), if the results are found in different cities.</p>
<p>For example, if you search for &#8220;lawyers+Madrid&#8221;, the results will be different if you are looking only in Madrid or if you are looking in Barcelona, despite the terms used in your query. The reason for this is that Google gives higher importance to the user&#8217;s IP address when deciding where to look.</p>
<h4 style="color:#5279b7">Slight changes to keywords yield different results</h4>
<p>Before changes were made to Google&#8217;s algorithm, if you searched for &#8220;lawyers in Madrid,&#8221; &#8220;Madrid lawyers,&#8221; or &#8220;Lawyer Madrid,&#8221; the results would have been either the same, very similar, or would have contained some of the same pages.</p>
<p>With the new algorithm, <strong>results are more variable, including for pages in 3-packs and searches with similar results included</strong>. This could mean that Google is still making changes to its algorithm in order to tweak and improve it.</p>
<h4 style="color:#5279b7">Local results, increasingly separate from organic search</h4>
<p>It seems that even if Google considers a page to be a duplicate and filters it through the SERP, it can still appear in local results. Additionally, <strong>some pages may appear</strong> as duplicates <strong>in both ordinary results and local 3-pack results</strong>, since these seem to be functioning separately. That would imply that some businesses may be benefiting from double visibility.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/everything-need-know-googles-possum-algorithm/">Everything you need to know about Google&#8217;s possum algorithm</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/everything-need-know-googles-possum-algorithm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to optimize product page content to boost sales</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/optimize-product-page-content-boost-sales/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/optimize-product-page-content-boost-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 18:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The product page is the cornerstone of your e-commerce website. Potential customers should be able to easily find and examine products, and get all the necessary details to prompt them to make a purchase. So it&#8217;s essential to analyze performance and optimize product pages when necessary. And that means improving the architecture and design of [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/optimize-product-page-content-boost-sales/">How to optimize product page content to boost sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The product page is the cornerstone of your e-commerce website. Potential customers should be able to easily find and examine products, and get all the necessary details to prompt them to make a purchase.<br />
So it&#8217;s essential to analyze performance and optimize product pages when necessary.<span id="more-22487"></span><br />
And that means improving the architecture and design of product pages, as well as content, in order to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Boost conversions</li>
<li>Optimize product pages on Google<br />
SEO consultants from Blog Ecommerce are here to show you how in today&#8217;s video:</li>
</ul>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Hnzs8dq3sWU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=blogecommerce"> Watch more vidéo</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/optimize-product-page-content-boost-sales/">How to optimize product page content to boost sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/optimize-product-page-content-boost-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Sell Faster&#8221;: Enhancing User Experience on a Daily Basis</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-faster-enhancing-user-experience-daily-basis/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-faster-enhancing-user-experience-daily-basis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastien Levaillant]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22468</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Code Better; Create Easier; Sell Faster&#8221;: PrestaShop 1.7 offers real improvements for everyone involved in creating an online shop: developers, theme designers and merchants. &#8220;Sell Faster&#8221; is designed for our users, merchants. The product department committed to making their lives easier. That is what user-oriented design is all about. When a merchant chooses PrestaShop, it [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-faster-enhancing-user-experience-daily-basis/">&#8220;Sell Faster&#8221;: Enhancing User Experience on a Daily Basis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Code Better; Create Easier; Sell Faster&#8221;: <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/1.7" target="_blank">PrestaShop 1.7</a> offers real improvements for everyone involved in creating an online shop: developers, theme designers and merchants.<span id="more-22468"></span></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Sell Faster&#8221; is designed for our users, merchants.</strong></p>
<p>The product department committed to making their lives easier. That is what user-oriented design is all about.</p>
<p>When a merchant chooses PrestaShop, it is for one simple reason: to be able to sell their products or services. </p>
<p>This may seem obvious, but what it implies is vital: if they are immediately given the full array of options offered by the software, they will feel overwhelmed.</p>
<p>E-commerce is becoming more and more common and some less experienced merchants are entering the market. We wanted to make the early stages of using our software easier, and support them during the first vital steps towards becoming an e-merchant.</p>
<p>Therefore, we focused on a few key tasks upon creating an online shop. The goal was to make them more intuitive and user-friendly.</p>
<p>Hence, the features were not seen as an end in itself, but rather as a &#8220;simple&#8221; means to accomplish these tasks.</p>
<p>More experienced users, i.e. companies looking for a powerful but simple software program after years in the e-commerce business, also wanted a more user-friendly product to support their development.</p>
<p>The 1.7.0 version is the result an analysis conducted on tens of thousands of e-shops and numerous interviews, surveys and tests.</p>
<p>As a result, we redesigned the user interface for:  </p>
<ul>
<li>Early Stages of Using PrestaShop: <br />
We have clearly indicated the 6 key steps to create your online shop. This simplified initial process is not mandatory. It is more of a guide to help you if you need it.</li>
<li>Creating Products: <br />
We made creating simple products less time-consuming. Instead of about fifteen minutes, it will now take you less than five. This is obviously essential, as without any products you will not receive any orders. We also made mass product creation easier by enabling the use of new file formats.</li>
</ul>
<p>Managing your shop from the back office is quicker and more efficient, and the product upload time has been reduced drastically. These two improvements favor a very short Time to Market, especially during key sales periods or internationalizations!</p>
<p>We have surveyed our user club and visited numerous merchants to have their feedback on how to improve user experience. If you also want to take part in our product tests, sign up to our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/club/" target="_blank">club</a>!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-faster-enhancing-user-experience-daily-basis/">&#8220;Sell Faster&#8221;: Enhancing User Experience on a Daily Basis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-faster-enhancing-user-experience-daily-basis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Holidays: 2015-2016 E-Commerce Trends and Outlook</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/christmas-holidays-2015-2016-e-commerce-trends-outlook/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/christmas-holidays-2015-2016-e-commerce-trends-outlook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 10:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cindy Deguingand]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22475</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Many of you in Europe and throughout the world* took part in our survey about preparing your online store for the holiday season. We made a promise and we&#8217;re keeping it! We have assessed the impact on your business and habits during that crucial peak sales time, the Christmas Holiday period. Find out about the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/christmas-holidays-2015-2016-e-commerce-trends-outlook/">Christmas Holidays: 2015-2016 E-Commerce Trends and Outlook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many of you in Europe and throughout the world* took part in our survey about preparing your online store for the holiday season. We made a promise and we&#8217;re keeping it!</p>
<p>We have assessed the impact on your business and habits during that crucial peak sales time, the Christmas Holiday period.</p>
<p>Find out about the 2015-2016 e-commerce trends and outlook. <span id="more-22475"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;font-weight: bold"><a title="Infographic : E-Commerce Trends &amp; Outlook 2016" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/christmas-holidays-2015-2016-e-commerce-trends-outlook/infographie_en/" target="_blank" rel="attachment wp-att-22520"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22520" alt="infographie_EN" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/12/infographie_EN.jpg" width="700" height="2277" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;font-weight: bold">2015 Report – Christmas Holiday period significant, but less so than last year with sales smoothed out over the year.</h2>
<p>The Christmas Holiday period is crucial for e-merchants.</p>
<p>This year, 29% of e-merchants surveyed estimate that the Christmas Holiday period represents between 10 and 25% of their revenue. 15% estimate that it represents more than 25%.</p>
<p>However, and this is a significant figure, more than half (57%) estimate that it represents less than 10% of their revenue. The Christmas Holiday share of revenue is thus decreasing, and e-merchants are managing to smooth their revenue more successfully over the year. The reason for that is the increase in promotional periods throughout the year: Black Friday, Cyber Monday, sales, Valentine&#8217;s Day, Mother’s Day, Father’s Day, etc. See our <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/11539-uk-ecommerce-calendar.html" target="_blank">e-commerce calendar</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;font-weight: bold">Outlook for the 2016 season</h2>
<p>The good news is that e-merchants are quite optimistic about their prospective sales this year: 72% estimate that their revenue will be higher than last year in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>Recruitment</strong> – 14% of online stores are planning to hire staff specifically for the holiday period. That is a good sign and can be correlated with the results of e-merchants for whom the holiday period represents more than 10% of their revenue (15% in total).</p>
<p>For those recruiting for the holiday period, the most sought-after profiles are mainly for <strong>staff to deal with taking orders and returned packages (28%).</strong> These are followed by <strong>e-mail and social media marketers (20%) and web developers (18%). </strong></p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;font-weight: bold">Christmas Holiday preparations</h2>
<p>76% of European e-merchants state that they prepare their online store for the Christmas Holiday period. 90% of them do so <strong>1 to 3 months in advance</strong>. So e-merchants decide on their main action plan for the Christmas Holidays <strong>in October</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>What are their 3 main objectives for this period?</strong></p>
<p><strong>1/ Preparing their online store</strong> – festive design, adding product pages, promotional offers, etc., all of which explain the importance of recruiting web designers and developers.</p>
<p><strong>2/ Preparing</strong> targeted <strong>promotional e-mail campaigns</strong> to boost the number of orders and the average cart size.</p>
<p><strong>3/ An optimum inventory level</strong>, neither too big nor too small, but one that strikes a happy medium to avoid being left with unsold stock after the holiday period, and to avoid having inventory shortages that result in the immediate loss of a sale.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;font-weight: bold">The mobile share of Christmas Holiday e-commerce revenue</h2>
<p>For e-merchants in a position to state this (78% of respondents), <strong>the share of revenue made via mobile devices over the holiday period is 17%</strong> on average.</p>
<p>However, almost 22% of respondents had no idea about the volume of mobile sales in their revenue.</p>
<p>From that we can conclude that there is still a considerable amount of room for optimizing e-commerce websites for mobile devices. Simple methods for assessing the volume of revenue from mobile devices can be set up via <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/features/mobile-site-traffic.html" target="_blank">Google Analytics</a>. This enables e-merchants to identify the most effective mobile platforms for their e-commerce.</p>
<h2 style="color: #251b5b;font-weight: bold">The importance of social media in an e-commerce marketing strategy</h2>
<p>Social media is considered to be important in the e-merchant&#8217;s marketing strategy in Poland: 57% consider it crucial in communications during the Christmas period, and 35% consider it to be quite important.</p>
<p>* Sample of those surveyed: <strong>1,305</strong> e-merchants active in Europe and <strong>1,898</strong> throughout the world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/christmas-holidays-2015-2016-e-commerce-trends-outlook/">Christmas Holidays: 2015-2016 E-Commerce Trends and Outlook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/christmas-holidays-2015-2016-e-commerce-trends-outlook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
